Guide to the Max S. Baucus Papers 1958-2016 (bulk 1974-2014)
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Photographs, 1958-2014; Series XIII; 29.6 linear feet; 281.9 gigabytes
  - Electronic Files, 1958-2014; Sub-series 5; 282 gigabytes
    - Senate, 1958-2014; Sub-sub-series 2; 279.0 gigabytes
      - Edward Kennedy, Max Baucus, Charles Rangel and others at CHIP reauthorization signing ceremony, February 4, 2009 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017350)
      - Barack Obama at CHIP reauthorization signing ceremony, February 4, 2009 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017351)
      - Barack Obama and Max Baucus, April 29, 2009 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017352)
      - Max Baucus, Barack Obama and others at Affordable Care Act signing ceremony, March 23, 2010 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017353)
      - Max Baucus at Big Dipper workday event, May 8, 2010 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017354)
      - Max Baucus signing a child's shirt at Governors Cup race, June 11, 2010 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017355)
      - Max Baucus and children in Butte Fourth of July parade, July 4, 2010 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017356)
      - Max Baucus hiking in Glacier National Park, August 20, 2010 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017357)
      - Max Baucus and Vice Premier Wang Qishan, October 10-16, 2010 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017358)
      - Max Baucus at Billings Optimist Club workday, December 11, 2010 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017359)
      - Max Baucus on trip to Colombia and Brazil, February 20-27, 2011 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017360)
      - Max Baucus and constituents at Farm Bill listening session, March 21, 2011 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017361)
      - Max Baucus during Briggs Distributing workday, September 29, 2011 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017362)
      - Max Baucus during Lakeside Tamarack Brewery workday, May 4, 2012 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017363)
      - Max Baucus pouring beer at brew fest, May 5, 2012 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017364)
      - Max Baucus during Simms Fishing workday, May 29, 2012 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017365)
      - Max Baucus at Barack Obama's second inaugural parade, January 21, 2013 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017367)
      - Max Baucus with Bozeman Stroller Brigade, April 20, 2013 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017368)
      - Max Bacuus and Big Sky Honor Flight participant Howard Largent, April 22, 2013 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017369)
      - Max Baucus and Doug Chadwick during a Montana Conservation Corps workday, August 8, 2013 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017370)
      - Max Baucus at the Montana Economic Development Summit, September 15, 2013 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017371)
      - Max Baucus at ambassadorial nomination hearing, January 28, 2014 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017372)
      - Max Baucus and constituents during whistle stop tour, January 31, 2014 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017373)
      - Max Baucus during Montana Conservation Corps workday, February 3, 2014 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017374)
      - Melodee Hanes, Max Baucus, and Joe Biden at ambassadorial swearing-in ceremony, February 21, 2014 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017375)
      - Max Baucus with Chinese officials, January 1, 2015 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017377)
      - Max Baucus and Melodee Hanes at ice and snow festival, January 1, 2015 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017378)
      - Max Baucus riding a camel, circa 2015 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017379)
      - Max Baucus releasing endangered sea turtle, circa 2015 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017380)
      - Max Baucus with schoolgirls, circa 2015 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017381)
      - Max Baucus in Shanxi Province, circa 2015 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017382)
      - Max Baucus touring USS Benfold, August 1, 2016 (Digital image Digital Image, Photo number umt017383)
    - Accession 2019-033, 2007-2011; Sub-sub-series 3; 565.7 megabytes
      Materials in this sub-subseries consist of photographs transferred to the repository in 2018 on optical media. These images were subsequently converted to a digital format by the processing archivist. They document a 2011 hike in Big Sky, Montana, a CODEL (Congressional Delegation) trip to Iraq in 2007, and trade trips to the United Arab Emirates and Vietnam in 2008. Original file and folder names have been retained.
- Audiovisual, 1955-2014; Series XIV; 959 audio and video recordings; 475.1 gigabytes
  This series consists of audiovisual material, both audio and video recordings. It covers the entirety of Baucus’s congressional career, particularly emphasizing campaign material, television appearances, and Committee hearings, and reflects more than three decades of continually-evolving audiovisual technology.
  It is divided into three subseries: Audio Recordings, Video Recordings, and Electronic Files.
  - Audio Recordings, 1978-2008; Sub-series 1; 203 audio recordings
    This subseries contains audio recordings which document field hearings, speeches, town hall meetings, interviews, news clips, campaign appearances, floor statements, and committee hearings in which Baucus took part. Topics range widely, and many of the audio recordings were recorded in towns in and around Montana. Campaign audio in this subseries is not limited to Max Baucus’s campaigns, and also covers the campaigns of some political opponents and allies, including Pat Williams and Allen Kolstad. Most, but not all, audio recordings include Baucus—some were generated during town hall meetings and field hearings at which Baucus was not present. All audiocassettes in this subseries were digitized by Baucus’s office, files which can be found in Subseries 3, Electronic Files.
  - Video Recordings, 1955-2014; Sub-series 2; 756 video recordings
    This subseries contains video recordings consisting of a variety of formats. Content includes committee hearings (including Environment and Public Works, Appropriations, Finance, and Agriculture), floor and hearing statements, speeches, interviews, public service announcements, town halls, news clips and talk show appearances, and campaign debates, ads, and statements. A variety of topics are covered, including foreign relations with Japan, Cambodia, and the Middle East, transportation, wilderness, tax reform, trade, and the asbestos crisis in Libby. Items with a VHS number have accompanying CD or DVD surrogates and were converted to digital files by Baucus staffers, which can be found in Subseries 3, Electronic Files.
  - Electronic Files, 1976-2014; Sub-series 3; 475.1 gigabytes
    This subseries contains digital audio and video recordings generated throughout Baucus’s political career. The majority of these recordings were converted from analog to digital formats by Baucus staffers, and consist of campaign advertisements, television debates, television and radio interviews, public service announcements, televised floor statements, and advertisements for events like the Montana Economic Development Summit and the Faith Community Impact Summit. Converted Optical Media consists of optical media items (CDs and DVDs) which were converted to more stable digital formats by archives staff, and an inventory of their contents is available upon request. The majority of original file and folder names have been retained, though some files have been renamed for clarity. While it is likely that many of these files are reflected in the analog portion of this series, exact correlations have not been fully established.
- Memorabilia, 1944-circa 2016; Series XV; 149 artifacts; 1.8 gigabytes
  This series contains a wide variety of awards and other memorabilia given to Baucus in recognition of his legislative and public service work. Items include framed workday photographs, ceremonial pens commemorating the signing of legislation, framed pieces of legislation, various awards and certificates reflecting Baucus’s lengthy running career, miscellaneous artworks, and campaign ephemera.
  The series is divided into two subseries: Artifacts and Electronic Files.
  This series is restricted until 2044.
  - Artifacts, 1944-circa 2016; Sub-series 1; 149 artifacts
    This subseries contains the physical artifacts which make up the analog portion of this series. Items within the original accession (acquisition) were surveyed, and selected artifacts were retained based on their historic, intrinsic, exhibit, and/or research value.
  - Electronic Files, 1975-2014; Sub-series 2; 1.8 gigabytes
    This subseries contains digital images of all awards originally contained within the Baucus Papers, including artifacts which were not retained. Original file names have been retained.
- Ambassadorial Files, 2014-2016; Series XVI; 1.1 gigabytes
  This series consists of digital records from Max Baucus's tenure as the United States Ambassador to the People's Republic of China. They include nomination endorsements from Montana leaders, Baucus's nomination statement to the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, photographs from his swearing-in ceremony, a video of Baucus encouraging Chinese companies to do business in the United States, and photographs from his time spent in China as Ambassador.
  Materials in this series, with the exception of photographs, are restricted until 2044.